<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>UC Santa Cruz - Fifty ways to be amazing</title>
    <description>In honor of the campus&#39;s 50th year — here are 50 ways to become just as amazing as UC Santa Cruz.</description>
    <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 16:10:25 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 16:10:25 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>50 share your passion</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our organic farm and garden program was the first established on a university campus. Today it is the country&amp;rsquo;s leading university program in sustainable agriculture and food systems and has pioneered the use of organic horticulture techniques internationally. More than 1,500 graduates of the Apprenticeship in Ecological Horticulture have fanned out around the globe, spreading the seeds of sustainable agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/50</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/50</guid>
        
        
        <category>list</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>49 waste not</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Why waste when you can compost? Last year, UC Santa Cruz Dining diverted 638 tons of kitchen and food scraps from the landfill, instead turning the waste into nutrient-rich compost, which was used to replenish the soil and grow more food. The University of California has set a goal of zero waste by 2020, and each campus has developed a Zero Waste Plan. In addition, UC Santa Cruz eats with a conscience. Our dining halls and cafes have already surpassed the UC system-wide goal of ensuring that 20 percent of food purchases are sustainably sourced, with locally grown fruits and vegetables, organic coffee, sustainably caught seafood, and cage-free eggs on our menus. We also are more than halfway to a campus target of 40 percent of food purchases meeting Real Food standards by 2020. Real Food is defined as food that is produced in a fair, humane, and sustainable manner.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/49</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/49</guid>
        
        
        <category>list</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>48 watch and learn</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;By pioneering the use of satellite tags to monitor the migrations of elephant seals, our researchers compiled one of the largest datasets available for any marine mammal species, revealing their movements and diving behavior at sea in unprecedented detail. The tags have recorded elephant seal dives to depths of well over a mile and documented their annual migrations throughout the entire northeast Pacific Ocean and as far as the Aleutian Islands in western Alaska, almost 3,000 miles from the rookery at Año Nuevo Island north of Santa Cruz.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/48</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/48</guid>
        
        
        <category>list</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>47 keep reserves</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our marine biologists-including Pete Raimondi, Mark Carr, and John Pearse-were actively involved in planning an unprecedented network of marine protected areas along the California coast, as called for in the 1999 Marine Life Protection Act. In addition to serving on science advisory teams, Raimondi and Carr are engaged in an intensive monitoring program to track the effects of the reserves on marine life. Their research in the Gulf of California, meanwhile, has confirmed the validity of a key concept behind marine reserves-the idea that offspring produced in a protected area can replenish the stocks of harvested species outside the reserve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/47</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/47</guid>
        
        
        <category>list</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>46 think globally</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While the vast majority of our students are California residents, we have always offered a distinctive world-class education, and our campus reflects a global population. Current students come from 47 states and 69 countries. Out-of-state and international students add important exposure to different cultures and perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/46</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/46</guid>
        
        
        <category>list</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>45 honor diversity</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;While the vast majority of our students are California residents, we have always offered a distinctive world-class education, and our campus reflects a global population. Current students come from 47 states and 69 countries. Out-of-state and international students add important exposure to different cultures and perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/45</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/45</guid>
        
        
        <category>list</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>44 start young</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With help from the campus&amp;rsquo;s Educational Partnership Center and other university personnel, we help students in five counties prepare for college and provide the opportunity for every 7th grader in Santa Cruz County to visit either our campus or another local university for a day. While on campus, the 7th graders learn about college eligibility and preparation, and engage with current UC Santa Cruz students.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/44</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/44</guid>
        
        
        <category>list</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>43 celebrate education</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We open the doors of higher education. Forty-two percent of graduates in 2015 were the first in their family to earn a four-year university degree. And 43 percent of incoming freshman students in fall 2015 are from families where neither parent has a four-year degree.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/43</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/43</guid>
        
        
        <category>list</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>42 cherish special things</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;McHenry Library&amp;rsquo;s Special Collections is, well-really special. In addition to the heavily used Lick Observatory Records, the department holds one of the nation&amp;rsquo;s most significant collections in the history of astronomy, including a one-of-a-kind manuscript of Johannes de Sacrobosco&amp;rsquo;s lunar computations, which was produced in Italy in the early 15th century.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/42</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/42</guid>
        
        
        <category>list</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>41 create a name for yourself</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Many of our colleges were named for donors:
For example, Cowell College is named for Henry Cowell and the Cowell family, former owners
of the campus site; Merrill College is named after Charles E. Merrill Jr., whose father, Charles E. Merrill Sr., was the founder of Merrill Lynch; Oakes College was named in 1975 after philanthropists Roscoe and Margaret Oakes; and Kresge College was originally endowed by the Kresge family trust, whose fortune was derived from discount department store chain Kmart. Colleges Eight, Nine, and Ten are as yet unnamed and still seeking eponymous philanthropists.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/41</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/41</guid>
        
        
        <category>list</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
